>> Jem Young: 好的，我们讨论了集装箱和
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: All right,
we talked about containers and
编排和弹性云计算。
orchestration and elastic cloud computing.
有人提醒我弹性云计算是什么。
Someone remind me what
elastic cloud computing is.
听起来就像这样
It's what it sounds like.
>> Jem Young: 是。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yes.
>> 演讲者 2: 根据您随时间的需求展开和签订合同。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: It expands and
contracts based on your needs over time.
>> Jem Young: 没错，这对
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Exactly,
and it's useful for,
我想我所举的例子是在节假日期间，有很多的流动。
I think the example I gave was during
the holidays there's a lot of streaming.
另一个例子是 " 前端大师" 。
Another example would be Frontend Masters.
午夜可能没有很多人在看，所以
At midnight, there might not be
a lot of people watching, so
他们可以减少一些资源
they can take down some of the resources.
白天，当更多的人在看的时候，他们把他们带回来。
And during the day, when more people
are watching, they bring them back up.
但我们用一个概念来了解服务器的负载
But we do that with a concept of
knowing the load of the servers and
然后说，哎，这个东西是 90% 的负荷。
then measuring that and saying like,
hey, this thing is at 90% load.
我们得去别的地方
We need to route traffic somewhere else.
或者我们有 10% 的负荷，实际上我们不需要这些服务器。
Or we're at 10% load,
we actually don't need these servers.
但是负载均衡器是将所有流量路由到相应集群的路由。
But a load balancer is what routes all
the traffic to the appropriate cluster.
它是你不考虑的事情直到你有了规模
And it's something that you don't
think about until you're at scale,
当你有两个服务器的时候
when you have even two servers.
我们将为一个示例使用两个服务器。
We'll take two servers for an example.
一个服务器可能会得到所有流量，因为这就是
One server might get all the traffic
because that's just the way
交通会被改道
the traffic's getting routed.
然后另一个服务器就没做任何事了
And then the other server,
it's just not doing anything.
只是在浪费循环
It's just wasting cycles.
但运行 90% 负载的问题是速度较慢。
But the problem with running
a 90% load is that's a bit slow.
而另一个服务器却没有做任何事情。
Whereas, the other server
is not doing anything.
这就是负载均衡器的概念。
That's where the concept of
a load balancer comes in.
它确保在所有服务器之间均匀分割流量。
It makes sure that traffic is split
evenly between all of your servers.
如果你有一万台服务器就不重要了
Cuz it doesn't matter if
you have 10,000 servers,
如果他们三个都在做这些他们其他人什么都没做
if three of them are doing all the work,
the rest of them aren't doing anything.
>> Jem Young: 负载均衡器使用称为调度算法的概念。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Load balancers work with
a concept called a scheduling algorithm.
我知道，这听起来很无聊，但对我来说，这是最有趣的部分。
I know, this sounds dull but this, to me,
is some of the most interesting parts.
好吧，你觉得这些调度算法是什么呢 ?
All right, what do you think some
of these scheduling algorithms do?
他们的名字叫
They're kinda in the name.
IP 散列有点棘手所以我不知道
The IP Hashing is a little tricky so
I don't.
如果你有 10 台服务器我就有个请求了
So think if you had ten servers and
I have a request coming in.
负载均衡器如何确定要运行哪个服务器 ?
How does the load balancer
determine which server it goes to?
这是调度算法的操作。
That's what a scheduling algorithm does.
那你觉得罗宾会怎么做
So, what do you think Round Robin does?
>> 扬声器 3: 转至序列中的下一个。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Just goes to
the next one in the sequence.
>> Jem Young: 完全正确，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Exactly,
that's exactly right,
这是大多数负载均衡器的缺省负载均衡器策略。
that's the default load balancer
strategy for most load balancers.
还有 IP 散列，将 IP 散列化。
There's also IP Hashing,
which hashes your IP.
这意味着它通过散列算法来运行
That means it runs it
through a hashing algorithm,
将其转换为一组字符，然后与另一组 IP 匹配。
converts it to a set of characters, then
matches that against a other set of IPs.
因此 IP 散列的好处是保证您可以访问同一服务器
So the benefit of IP Hashing is that
you're guaranteed to go to the same server
每次都是基于您的 IP 地址。
every time based on what
your IP address is.
也有随机的
There's also just random.
有趣的是我们花了很多时间
And what's funny is we've
spent a lot of time and
对调度算法的研究。
research into scheduling algorithms.
但 Random Choice 其实挺好的
But Random Choice actually
works pretty well,
随便选一个服务器就行了
just picking a random server works okay.
这不是默认值，但实际上不是一个糟糕的策略。
It's not the default, but
it's actually not a bad strategy.
也有最少的连接。
There's also Least Connections.
因此，这意味着负载均衡器需要知道每个单值上的负载是什么
So that means the load balancer needs to
know what the load is on every single
服务器，说该服务器有 20 个连接，这个有 10 个。
server and it's saying this server
has 20 connections, this one has 10.
我要去那个有 10个的人
I'm gonna go to the one that has 10.
还有载荷的概念。
There's also the concept of load.
因此，如果您具有真正的过程密集型应用程序，那么
So if you have really process-intensive
applications, the server with
最少量的量会得到更多的流量直到它平衡。
the least amount of load is gonna get more
of the traffic until it balances out.
就像我说的， Round Robin 是大多数负载均衡器的默认值。
And like I said, Round Robin is
the default on most load balancers.
现在让我们来看一下我们的服务器负载是什么，让我们来运行。
So let's take a look at what our server
load is right now, let's run top.
>> Jem Young: 因此，我们可以说最上面的内容。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So
to run top, we can say top.
>> Jem Young: 这让我们实时查看
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And this gives us
a real-time view of what's happening on
我们的服务器
our server.
它告诉我们我们有多少线程
It tells us the amount of
threads we have available,
也许我们只会有一个 CPU
which is probably gonna be
one cuz we only have one CPU.
还有多少 RAM ，之类的，而且是实时的，所以
How much RAM there is, things like that,
and it's real-time, so
一直都在跟踪
it's always keeping track.
你不想一直跑这么大
You don't wanna run top all the time,
因为顶部本身需要资源 [LAUGH] 才能运行。
because top itself takes
resources [LAUGH] to run.
在我们的小服务器上如果你一直在运行
And on our single tiny little server,
if you're running top all the time,
你会看到资源消耗上升
you'd see the resource consumption go up.
但说实话这不是用户友好的问题
But honestly,
this isn't that user friendly.
我可以分解它
I could break it down.
我可以写一个剧本来提取告诉我的一切
I could write a script that extracts
out everything that this is telling me
详细说明。
in detail.
但让我们安装一些小一点的清洁装置。
But let's install something
a little bit cleaner.
让我们安装 htop ，并从顶部退出 Q。
Let's install htop, and
to quit out of top, Q.
>> Jem Young: 我们安装 htop，它有点 nicer。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And let's install htop,
which is a little bit nicer.
因此， sudo apt 安装 htop。
So sudo apt install htop.
>> Jem Young: 我想其实已经安装了。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And
it's actually already installed, I think.
所以我们现在就跑吧
So let's just run htop now.
太酷了
That's much cooler.
这就是你能在电脑上留下的东西
This is one of those things you
can leave up on your computer and
人们会走过来，他们在做什么 ?
people'll walk by like,
what are they working on?
他们一定很聪明看看这些数字
They must be really smart,
look at all those numbers!
但它与顶部完全相同，只是一个更漂亮的格式。
But it's really the same thing as top,
it's just in a prettier format.
它告诉我们我们的 CPU 负载，我们的内存消耗。
And it tells us our CPU load,
our memory consumption.
有趣的是，如果我们看看所有 CPU的使用情况， htop 在顶部附近。
Funny enough, if we look at what's using
up all the CPU, htop is near the top.
[ LAUGH] 它用大量的 CPU 来运行这个
[LAUGH] It's using a lot
of CPU just to run this.
如果我们转至 Fn+F7，等待，不需要树方式， F5。
And if we go to Fn+F7, wait,
no I want the tree mode, F5.
记得我说 PM2 能帮助集群吗
Remember I said PM2 can
help with clustering?
它会将您的节点的多个实例
It'll actually spin up multiple
instances of your Node
向您申请，并将其添加到您。
application for you and it adds and
subtracts them for you.
我们可以看到，这 PM2 是运行节点，但也在运行
We can see that here, that PM2 is running
node but it's also running all these
节点的不同实例以及 PM2的所有这些不同实例。
different instances of node and there's
all these different instances of PM2.
这就是树的模式。
So that's just tree mode.
>> Jem Young: 但是，如果您的系统运行速度较慢，正在运行顶部或顶部
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: But really, if your system
is running slow, running top or htop is
能把我的所有 CPU 周期都拉上来吗 ?
a good thing to pull up and say what
exactly is using up all my CPU cycles?
麦肯等价会是，让我们说， " 活动监控器" 。
The Mac equivalent would be,
let's say, Activity Monitor.
我可以在一个更清洁的 UI上为我的 Mac 启动 Activity Monitor 。
And I can pull up Activity Monitor for
my Mac in a much cleaner UI.
我们可以看到 Activity Monitor 实际上是 [LAUGH] 使用我的所有 CPU ，但是
And we can see that Activity Monitor is
actually [LAUGH] using up all my CPU, but
一般都是 Chrome 的主犯或 VS 码
it's generally gonna be Chrome
as the main culprit or VS Code.
但最重要的是知道你的负担
But top is just a good
thing to know your load.
当我们谈到负载均衡器时，这就是我们所说的，
And so when we talk about load balancers,
this is what we're talking about,
了解 CPU 负载，连接负载，内存负载。
understanding the CPU load,
the connection load, the memory load.
要退出，我只能按 Ctrl+C，我想，或者实际上是 F10。
And to quit, I can just Ctrl+C,
I think, or actually F10.
>> 扬声器 4: 内存部分中的颜色代码是什么，您知道吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: What are the color codes
in the memory section, do you know?
>> Jem Young: 我不知道权威，但是
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: I don't
know authoritatively, but
我想说绿色还可以
I wanna say green is you're still okay.
我想我们是蓝色的所以我们要接近一半
I think we're in blue, so
we're getting close to halfway.
我想当你更进一步时，它会改变颜色。
And I think when you get a little further,
it's gonna change colors.
等等我可能是向后看的
Wait, I might have that backwards.
我不能确切地说颜色码是什么意思
I couldn't say authoritatively
what the color codes mean exactly.
> > Jem Young: 我想说红色是不好的，但有时是红色的，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: I wanna say red would be
bad, but sometimes this goes in the red,
我不知道那是什么意思
which I don't know what that means.
可能是指正在使用或不使用 CPU 。
Maybe it means the CPU is being used or
not.
如果有人知道你可以把它推给我
If anybody knows, you can tweet it at me.
我们要离开这里了 F10我们又回来了
And we're just gonna quit out of here,
so F10, and we're back.
>> Jem Young: 我之前说 Nginx 是所有行业的千斤顶。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And earlier I said
Nginx is the jack-of-all-trades.
你知道吗
Well, you know what?
我们可以使用 Nginx 作为负载均衡器，因为它很酷。
We can use Nginx as a load balancer,
too, because it's just that cool.
因为我们只有一个服务器所以我们今天就不实施了
We're not gonna implement one today
because we only have one server, so
真的没什么可平衡的
there's really nothing to balance to.
但是如果我们有两台服务器或三台服务器，我们会添加这个上游的后端。
But if we had two servers or three
servers, we add this upstream backend.
然后， proxy_pass 将所有连接传递到一个。
And then we proxy_pass
all connections to one.
因此，我们可以在不同的服务器上运行 Node 应用程序，或者
So what we can do is we can run a Node
application on different servers or
不同的聚类。
different clusters.
然后如果我们向其中一个提供 proy_pass ，
And then if we proxy_pass to one of them,
and
Nginx 根据我们使用的服务器的策略来决定。
Nginx decides based on the strategy
we're using which server to go to.
太好了
That's pretty nice.
所以从盒子里我可以用一个 Nginx 负载运行 1000 台服务器
So out of the box, I could probably
run 1,000 servers with one Nginx load
它就会完美地处理交通
balancer and it's just gonna
handle the traffic perfectly.
我们可以在上游后端设置策略。
We can set the strategy
in the upstream backend.
如果你在这一点上你的资源非常密集
If you ever get to this point where you
have a very high resource intensive
我们可以说 least_conn
service, we can say least_conn.
这就意味着我们要用最少的连接服务
That just means we're gonna use
the least connection service.
这很棒 Nginx 为你做的
Which is awesome that Nginx does this for
you.
将其自动连接到服务器，获取负载，
Cuz it automatically connects to a server,
gets the load,
每一个我都不知道几毫秒
reports back every, I don't know,
couple milliseconds or so.
它会报告您每次有多少连接。
And it reports back how many
connections you have every single time.
我们也能做圆圆罗宾
We can also do Round Robin.
我们可以做 IP 散列之类的
We could do IP Hashing, things like that.
我不知道我是否谈到了粘性会话。
I don't know if I talked
about sticky sessions.
说实话我喜欢 Nginx 很棒的软件
Honestly, I love Nginx,
it's great software.
这些都是给你的
It does all these things for you.
从字面上来说，我可以用成百上千的方式运行整个 Web 应用程序
Literally, I can run entire web
applications with hundreds of
服务器仅具有 Nginx ，它将无缝工作。
servers with just Nginx and
it would work seamlessly.
但有个问题要问你，会议数据呢 ?
But here's a question for
you, what about session data?
那么，如果我登录到服务器呢 ?
So, what if I log into a server?
我在这台服务器上被授权了
I am authorized on this one server.
我该如何知道我不会被路由到未登录的其他服务器 ?
How do I know that I won't get routed to a
different server where I'm not logged in?
这是我遇到的一个真正的问题。
And this is a real
problem that I run into.
现在主要解决了，但是你认为会发生什么呢 ?
It's mostly solved now, but
what do you think would happen there?
>> 扬声器 5: 那么它取决于您是否正在使用粘性会话。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 5: Well, it depends on
if you're using sticky sessions.
>> Jem Young: 什么是粘性会话?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: What's a sticky session?
>> 扬声器 5: 将您粘贴到特定服务器上
&gt;&gt; Speaker 5: It's sticks you
to a particular server so
你不会被人碰的
you don't get bumped between them.
>> Jem Young: 没错，这是我们不考虑的事情，直到你必须要
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Exactly, it's something
we don't think about until you have to
实现某种登录或授权功能。
implement some sort of login or
authorization function.
就像这样我们会投以负载均衡器
Be like, yeah,
we'll throw in load balancers,
我要 20 台服务器我很好
I'll spin up 20 servers, I'm good.
但是我登录了但我点击链接或刷新页面
But then I'm logged in, but
I hit a link or refresh the page and
我不再登录了
I'm no longer logged in.
太令人沮丧了
That's frustrating,
因为负载均衡器可以每次将我路由到不同的服务器。
because the load balancer can route me
to a different server every single time.
解决这一问题的方式是 IP 散列。
Ways of solving that would be IP Hashing.
所以这意味着当我散列 IP 时
So that means when I hash the IP,
我每次都要去同一台服务器
I'm always gonna go to
the same server every time.
另一种方法就是在我们之前
Another way would just be implementing
an authorization layer before we
甚至打 Nginx
even hit Nginx.
所以它只会让我完全得到授权
So it just makes sure I'm
authorized completely.
如果不是我就把我退回去
If I'm not, it just bounces me out.
如果我授权的话，就转服务器了，我就不重要了
If I am authorized, it just goes to the
server and it doesn't matter if I'm logged
因为我们知道我们穿过了防火墙
it or not, because we know we
passed through that firewall.
想想当我们想到我们不能盲目地
It's something to consider when we
think about we can't just blindly
执行任务。
implement things.
正如 [LAUGH] Nginx 一样，这些都是我们必须做的考虑。
As easy as [LAUGH] Nginx makes it to be,
these are considerations we have to make.